203-598-6307



diascece@gmail.com

 $\boxtimes$ 

www.linkedin.com/in/ceceliafowler

in

https://github.com/cecelia001

CECELIA FOWLER

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Bootcamp Certificate CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain | 2022

Master of Science | Education
University of Bridgeport | CT | 2015

Bachelor of Science | Education
Western CT State University | CT | 2013

## **PROJECTS**

# **Roadtrip Planner Social Platform**

Worked with an international team to create a full stack app with authorization and 3rd party API integration. Built with: JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Bootstrap

## **Productivity Tracker**

Inherited legacy code to implement authentication and authorization, allowing for user registration and login. Built with: JSON Web Token, Bcrypt, JavaScript, React, MySQL, Chakra UI

#### **Monthly Expense Analysis**

Full stack app creating individualized budget limits and expense tracking Built with: JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Express/ NodeJS, MySQL, RESTful APIs

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript • Express •

React/Vue • NodeJS •

HTML/CSS • MySQL •

Bootstrap • TDD/JEST •

Sass • Advanced Git •

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

Full Stack Engineer with graduate level training in education and 4+ years managerial experience. Practical experience building applications from start to finish, including working with SQL and REST APIs, performing unit testing, and implementing front-end frameworks, like Vue. Lifelong learner with a diverse range of certifications and a strong desire to expand my knowledge and skills.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Full Stack Developer**

CodeOp | Barcelona, Spain | 2022

Three months of intensive full time bootcamp covering full stack technologies: JavaScript ES6+, ReactJS, ReactContext API, Node/Express and MySQL, and more. Built 3 full stack projects.

#### **Head of Youth Services**

Howard Whittemore & Terryville Library | Naugatuck, CT | 2018-2022 Supervised and trained staff of 9 and 15 volunteers. Oversaw short & long term budgets of \$15k. Fostered 6 new partnerships within the community. Boosted attendance of programs by 35%.

#### **Financial Advisor**

AXA Advisors | Milford, CT | 2016-2018

Advised a total of \$6 AUM in retirement accounts. Communicated regularly with over 130 clients, using Salesforce. Generated 15+ new leads weekly. Maintained all related licensing, compliance requirements and training.

## **Classroom Teacher**

Regional District 16 | Prospect, CT | 2013-2016

Developed instruction to meet diverse learning needs. Monitored student performance and prepared weekly reports to present at team meetings. Increased reading and math scores by 30%.

### LEADERSHIP

2018-2022

Early Childhood Council Representative 2019

Connecticut EXCITE
Collaborative Innovator